# Lucas Fredegoto Rinaldi

# Full Stack Developer

Mobile: (43) 996168589 Portfolium: rinaldilucas.com
Email: lucasreinaldi@gmail.com
CitHub: github.com/rinaldilucas
Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/rinaldilucas/
Telegram: t.me/rinaldilucas

#### **Personal Statement**

Working with computers since 2014 and programming since 2016, I've contributed to amazing people and worked on projects and websites that impacted millions of users. Always concerned with the user experience and using metrics to achieve the best retention rates.

### **Work Experience**

# > Forlogic — Full Stack Developer, at Cornélio Procópio

May 2023 - present

ForLogic is a software development company focused on quality assurance, serving clients such as Unimed, BRK, and Cia Iguaçu.

- Inspection and correction of the software development company's improvement and bug queue using Kanhan
- Development and maintenance of internally consumed APIs for web apps and mobile devices.
- Development of new features using Scrum.
- Responsible for a more than 500% improvement in build time by adding hot reload to an internal company library.
- Continuous refactoring of applications using clean code concepts, both in rewriting and defining ESLint and Prettier rules.
- Implementation of tasks and workspaces for C# development using VSCode.
- Contributing to the squad with VSCode configurations focused on productivity.
- Responsible for peer code reviews.

# > <u>Slingshot Digital</u> — Front-end Developer, at São Paulo

September 2023 - present

Slingshot is a web development producer that promotes solutions in campaign and platform development, serving clients such as McDonald's, HP, Samsung, Troller, and other brands.

- Creating pages from prototypes often using PHP/laravel with Blade Framework and also handlebars.js with marionette.js.
- Development of new features for existing applications/for release.
- · Facelifts and general layout changes.
- Estimation and definition of delivery times.
- Maintenance of the bugs queue of maintained projects.
- Metrics implementation and testing (Adobe Audience Manager, Facebook Pixel, Google Tag Manager).
- Using the Adobe package for image/video editing.
- Responsible for deployment in approval and production.

# > Forlogic — Junior Full Stack Developer, at Cornélio Procópio

August 2019 - September 2020

- Migration of the organization's digital products from the MVC model to Angular, using REST API (C#) and Scrum as an agile methodology.
- Maintenance of the company's legacy product bug queue using the Kanban methodology.
- Development and maintenance of APIs consumed internally and offered as services.
- Creation and refactoring of unit tests using xUnit.

## > Infinite Cloud — Junior Front-end Developer, at Londrina

September 2018 - January 2019

Infinite Cloud is a development agency focused on Marketing, promoting campaigns, and developing websites on demand, serving clients such as Unifil and PEC.

- Development of web projects such as e-commerce, institutional sites, portfolios, and websites in general.
- Consulting and monitoring advertising on Facebook and Google AdWords.
- Production, development, and artistic application focused on the web.
- Responsible for deploying and releasing the developed products.
- Testing and refactoring old code.

## > **S4W** — Full Stack Trainee Developer, at Cornélio Procópio

September 2016 — February 2017

S4W is a marketing agency with web development, which carries out and launches campaigns and web development on demand, serving clients such as Aguativa, UTFPR, and Rotary Club.

- Web development from prototypes (Photoshop).
- Database maintenance (SQL server).
- Development and logical coding of projects (ASP.NET and C#).
- Refactoring and graphical improvements of existing projects.
- Testing and refactoring old code.

## > **Town Hall** — Infrastructure Intern, at Cornélio Procópio

December 2013 - January 2015

The municipality of Cornélio Procópio has a technology sector, which helps internally and externally the needs related to the city's IT.

- Maintenance of hardware and software equipment used on the premises of the Municipality of Cornélio Procópio.
- Optimization and better use of physical computing resources.
- On-site and remote technical support.
- Assistance in the installation of the internal infrastructure.

## > **Unimed** — Minor Apprentice in Operations, at Cornélio Procópio

May 2012 - May 2013

Unimed is a Brazilian medical cooperative system that operates as a health plan operator.

- Half of the working period to carry out courses such as administration, financial management, information technology, taxation, morals, duty, ethics, mathematics, communication, leadership, and logical thinking.
- Analysis and completion of documentation with a focus on digital innovation (migration from physical to digital system).
- On-site and remote operational support.

#### **Academic Education**

january 2014 - june 2017

## **Degree in Systems Analysis and Development**

Federal Technological University of Northern Paraná - Cornélio Procópio, Paraná

## **Tech Stack**

- HTML5 - Git & GitHub - Kanban & SCRUM - Linux - CSS3 / LESS / SASS - Git Kraken & Git Flow - Windows - Protractor & Jest - JavaScript ES5+ - Domain and web host - REST & RESTful - macOS - SEO - Grunt / Gulp / Webpack 5 - Docker / AWS / GCloud - PHP / Laravel - Angular 2+ - NodeJS / Express.js / MongoDB - C# - XUnit / PhpUnit - Python - JWT and Auth middlewares - Marionette.js - Handlebars.js - Adobe XD - Photoshop & Illustrator - Figma

## **Academic References**

## Master Adriane Carla Anastácio

at UTFPR, Cornélio Procópio Campus anastacio@utfpr.edu.br

#### **Doctor Luciano Tadeu Esteves**

at UTFPR, Cornélio Procópio Campus luciano@utfpr.edu.br

#### Languages

- Portuguese (native) - English (advanced) - Spanish (basic)

## Certifications

#### Intermediate English, 480 hours

at CCAA 2006 - 2008

# Specialization in Hardware, Web Design, Algorithms, Graphic Design, Administration

at CENAIC

2010 - 2012

#### **Apprentice**

at Unimed with CIEE/SENAC partnership 2012 – 2013

# Several specialization courses focused on Technology, Full Stack and Leadership (see certifications)

at Alura

2020 - present